（ﾚﾅ）
人って 幸せになるために―
I wonder how much
effort is needed...
どれだけの努力が許されるのかな？
...for a person to become happy.
（ﾚﾅ）不幸ってね
連鎖するものだと思うの
I think misfortunes
cause chain reactions.
Once it starts,
it's difficult to get out of it.
一度 始まると
なかなか抜け出せない
In order to escape,
it takes great effort.
そこから抜け出すには
本当の本当に精いっぱい…
そこまでするのかって
いうくらい努力して―
You can finally grasp it
after you give it your very best.
やっと つかめる
それが
幸せってものじゃないかなって―
I think that is
what happiness means.
レナは思うの
（ﾚﾅ）でも だからって みんなにも
それを受け入れてもらおうなんて
But even so...
...I guess I'm not going
to expect everyone to accept that.
甘えるつもりはないかな
Rena!
（圭一(けいいち)）レナ！
（ﾚﾅ）ンッ！
Then let's begin.
じゃ 始めるよ！
竜宮(りゅうぐう)レナ
一世一代の頑張り物語を！
Rena Ryugu's once-in-a-lifetime
story of endeavor!
- "Atonement" Chapter -
Episode 01: HAPPINESS
When They Cry
Furimuita sono ushiro no
(shoumen dare)?
Kurayami ni tsume wo tatete
(yoru wo hikisaita).
Amadare wa chi no shizuku to
natte nodo wo tsutai ochiru.
Mou dokonimo kaeru
basho ga nai nara...
...kono yubi tomare
watashi no yubi ni.
Sono yubi goto tsuretette ageru.
Higurashi ga naku
akazu no mori e.
Atomodori wa mou dekinai.
（圭一）覚悟 魅音(みおん)！
Prepare yourself, Mion!
（魅音）甘いわ 圭ちゃん！
That's lame, Kei-chan!
（歓声）
（富田(とみた)）うまい！
Cool!
（岡村(おかむら)）これで残りは
レナさんと沙都子(さとこ)ちゃんだけだ！
Now only Rena-san
and Satoko-chan are left!
Maebara-san, do your best!
（富田･岡村）前原(まえばら)さん 頑張れ！
（沙都子）
おーほっほっほっほっ！
（沙都子）最初の威勢は どこへ
行ってしまいましたのかしら？
Where did all that energy
you had at the beginning go?
（沙都子）
おーほっほっほっほっ！
プロはターゲットの弾数も
ちゃんと把握しておくものですわ
A pro should know the number
of shots a target has left.
最後の１発分の水量では―
I bet the bit of water for your
last shot won't even reach me.
射程距離も
ほとんどないんじゃありません？
それは どうかな？
We'll see about that.
I planned to run here
when I ran out of shots...
ここには弾切れになったら
逃げ込もうと考えててね
あらかじめ １丁 隠してあったの
...so I hid a gun in advance.
チッ… レナのヤツ やるじゃねえか
That Rena's pretty good.
さ～てね
（圭一）えっ？
We'll see.
相手は
トラップの申し子 沙都子だよ
Her opponent is Satoko,
the holy child of traps.
That gun was
also important to me.
（沙都子）その１丁は
私にとっても大切な１丁でしたのよ
I wonder why.
（ﾚﾅ）どうしてかな？
だって その１丁がなかったら―
Because if you didn't have it...
レナさんは さっきの銃のまま―
...you wouldn't have
come forth with that gun.
私の前に姿を現したりしませんもの
（ﾚﾅ）えっ？
水鉄砲なんて
ちょっと砂粒を入れて空撃ちすれば
If you put a little sand in a water
gun and fire some shots...
...then it quickly
gets clogged, you know.
す～ぐに詰まっちゃうんですのよ
おーほっほっほっほっ！
Whoa.
（魅音）レナが隠したことを
知ってて 細工したってわけか！
She knew about
the hidden gun and altered it.
I have always said to leave
a slight trap for the end.
（沙都子）
私 いつも言ってましてよ
“トラップは 最後の最後に
ほんの１つ ささやかに”
これが究極の美徳でございましてよ
（ﾚﾅ）エヘヘッ…
That's what you call
the greatest virtue of all.
沙都子ちゃんも まだまだ甘いね
Satoko-chan, you're still naïve.
What did you say?
（沙都子）なんですって？
Do you recall
the rules for getting shot?
被弾の定義 覚えてる？
“水鉄砲の水に触れたら
被弾とし 負けとする”
If you're hit by a water gun's
water, then you're shot and lose.
うん？ それが 一体…
What's that mean?
（沙都子）ウウッ…
そんな使い方があったなんて…
To think you'd use it like that...
You need to be more cautious.
（ﾚﾅ）まだまだ詰めが甘かったね！
Rena!
レナー！
（ﾚﾅ）
最後は一騎打ちになると思ってたよ
I knew it'd end up one on one.
I have more respect for you.
You showed some great guts.
（圭一）見直したぜ
とんでもない根性
見せてくれるじゃねえか
（ﾚﾅ）見直したより
ホレ直したのほうが うれしいかな
Instead of respect, I'd like you
to fall in love with me again.
If you lose for me, that's fine.
（圭一）
負けてくれたら それでもいいぜ
I won't, would I?
それはイヤ …かな
この緊張感 たまらねえぜ
I love this tension.
I'll feel like a killjoy
if we settle this.
決着がつくことすら
興ざめするくらいにな
Don't blame me if you lose.
負けても恨まないでね
（圭一）勝負！
Let's fight!
ど… どっちが勝ったんですの？
Who won?
（梨花(りか)）
み～！ 判定は どうなのですか？
Mi, what's the judgment?
え～…
今日の２人は全く見事だったよ
You two were
absolutely brilliant today.
圭ちゃんもレナも
最高の力を発揮してくれた
Both Kei-chan and Rena
gave it their very best.
That instantaneous power has
been elevated beyond beauty.
その瞬発力は もはや
美しいと呼べるまでに昇華され
Therefore, it's impossible
to decide who won.
とてもじゃないが
優劣をつけることはできない
Then how will
we conclude the match?
じゃ 決着は どうなるんですの？
本日の戦いを預かり勝負とし―
The winner will not
be decided today...
後日
改めて決着をつけることとしたい！
...so the battle will be
settled on a later date!
Hold on!
ちょっと待った！
（魅音･沙都子）ギクッ！ ドキッ！
Shoot.
（ﾚﾅ）うん ちょっと
流すわけにはいかないかな
I don't think I can
let that slide, maybe.
W-What do you two want?
み～？
（魅音）な… 何かな？ ２人とも
I'll agree to a rematch.
（圭一）
再試合は よしとしよう　だが…
But...
...Mion, Satoko, and Rika-chan!
魅音に 沙都子に 梨花ちゃん！
Are you prepared for
your punishment game?
罰ゲームの覚悟 できてるよね？
ギクッ！
（沙都子）ドキッ！
- Shoot.
にぱ～！
Ni-pa~.
Dessert Fair
（梨花）いらっしゃいませ
Welcome.
Welcome to Angel Mort.
エンジェルモートへ
ようこそなのですよ
はぅ～！ かぁいいよ！
So cute! I'm taking you home!
お持ち帰り～！
ウ～ン！
なんという至極の罰ゲーム
What an extreme
punishment game.
（梨花）ジロジロ見られると
恥ずかしいのです み～…
It's embarrassing
when you stare at me.
（富田･岡村）
ク～ッ！ たまらない！
It's too much!
アアッ…
富田君 岡村君 どうして？
Tomita-kun,
Okamura-kun, why...
Never mind that, Maebara-san.
愚問です 前原さん！
Forget that. There, there, there!
（岡村）それにつけても
あちら！ あちら！ あちら！
あちらも見てください
（圭一）えっ？
Look over there!
ウルトラレアチーズケーキ
お待たせしました！
Here's your order
of ultrarare cheesecake.
魅ぃちゃんも かぁいいよ！
Mi-chan, you're cute too.
Gosh, this is
the greatest misfortune.
ああ もう とんでもない災難だよ
この格好は 圭ちゃんに
やらせるつもりだったのにな
I was planning for
Kei-chan to wear this.
Well, just be prepared for
the next punishment game.
まあ せいぜい 次回の罰ゲームは
覚悟しておくことですわ
Satoko-chan's maid outfit is
so cute! I'm taking her home!
沙都子ちゃんのメイド かぁいいよ
お持ち帰り～！
（入江(いりえ)）そうは させませ～ん！
I won't let you do that!
お持ち帰るのは
この私 入江京介(きょうすけ)です
The one taking her
home will be Kyosuke Irie.
- Where'd you come from?
- No! No! No!
あんた どっから？
（ﾚﾅ）ダメダメ ダメ～！
If you interfere
with my take-homes...
レナのお持ち帰りをジャマすると
はぅ～！
（殴る音）
（入江）いたた！ あいたた…
（ﾘﾅ）えっ？ 満席なの？ ウソ！
（義郎(よしろう)）申し訳ありません
You're full? No way.
I'm sorry.
（入江）お持ち帰り～！
Oh, Reina-chan.
（ﾘﾅ）あら 礼奈(れいな)ちゃんじゃない
こんなとこで会うなんて奇遇ね
What a coincidence
meeting you here.
あっ リナさん　どうも こんにちは
Rina-san.
Good afternoon.
聞いてよ 礼奈ちゃん　ひどいのよ
満席で入れないとか言うのよ
Listen to this,
Reina-chan. It's terrible.
They're not letting me
in because they're full.
（ﾚﾅ）
ああ ハハッ… そうみたいですね
It seems so.
Even if I can't sit down...
ねえ お店には入れなくても―
お土産のケーキくらいは
売ってくれるんでしょう？
...you'll at least let me
buy a cake as a gift, right?
（義郎）
ええ それは問題ございません
Yes, that won't be a problem.
Please pick which one you want.
どうぞ こちらから
どれでも お選びください
あの人はショートケーキみたいな
地味なのが好きだったっけ？
Didn't he like simple
ones like shortcakes?
Hey, Reina-chan.
Which do you like?
ねえ 礼奈ちゃん
あなたは どれがいい？
えっ 私ですか？
いいの いいの？ はぅ～！
Me? Can I? Can I?
Choose whichever you like.
（ﾘﾅ）好きなの選んでいいわよ
（ﾚﾅ）えっと えっと…
Um... Um... This one!
じゃ これ　はぅ～！
（ﾘﾅ）そう
Oh, then two shortcakes
and one petit trianon.
じゃ ショートケーキを２つと
プチトリアノンを１つ
“お持ち帰り～”でね
（義郎）ありがとうございます
To go please.
Thank you very much.
（圭一）俺さ
前は都会に住んでたわけだけどさ
I used to live in
urban cities, you know.
（ﾚﾅ）うん？
（圭一）こんなにも―
I never lived each day
having this much fun.
１日１日を楽しいと思って
過ごしたことはなかった
俺 雛見沢(ひなみざわ)に引っ越してきてさ
きっと幸せなんだって思う
I think moving to Hinamizawa...
...made me realize
how happy I was.
I feel the same way.
レナも同じだよ
You see, I also moved
to Hinamizawa a year ago...
ほら 私も１年前に
雛見沢に引っ越してきたわけだけど
...but I can't believe how every
day can be this fun and happy.
こんなに楽しい幸せな日々を
送れるのが信じられないもの
こんなにも毎日が楽しいと…
But since every day is so fun...
...it's scary to think how
it might fall apart one day.
なんだか
ある日 突然 転びそうで怖いよな
When you fall, you fall no
matter how cautious you are.
（ﾚﾅ）転ぶときは
どんなに注意してても転ぶよ
だから
いつ転んでもいいように―
I think it's right to live every day
fully, so you're ready if it does.
思いっきり
今を楽しむのが正解だと思うな
（圭一）そうだな
今を精いっぱい楽しむのが正解だな
That's true.
It's right to live fully.
I think I'll go
treasure hunting again.
さて
レナは また宝探しに行こうかな
まだ遊び足りないってのかよ？
You still want to have fun?
Would you like
to come along too?
どう？ 良かったら
圭一君も一緒に来ない？
パ～ス！
I'll pass.
天気も怪しそうだし
The weather's
a little unstable too.
レナも今日は おとなしく
帰ったほうがいいんじゃないか？
Wouldn't it be better for
you to go home today?
はぅ～！
こういうステキな気分の日はね
When I feel happy like I do today,
I'm sure I'll find something cute.
きっと
かぁいいのが見つかるんだよ
だから 行ってみるね ウフフフッ…
So I'm gonna go, okay?
（圭一）うん 分かったよ
Yeah, got it.
See you later.
じゃあな
（ﾚﾅ）うん じゃあね バイバ～イ！
Later. Bye-bye!
Reina-chan,
do you remember that man...
（ﾚﾅの母）礼奈ちゃん この間
映画とお食事に行ったとき―
...who we watched a movie
with and had dinner with?
一緒だった人のこと覚えてる？
Um, wasn't his name Akihito?
（ﾚﾅ）う～んと…
アキヒトおじさんだっけ？
Reina-chan,
do you like Akihito-san?
（母）礼奈ちゃんは
アキヒトさんのこと 好き？
Hey, Reina-chan, who do you
like better, Mommy or Daddy?
（母）ねえ 礼奈ちゃんは
お母さんとお父さんと―
どっちが好き？
（ﾚﾅ）お母さん
Mommy.
もしも お母さんとお父さんが
別々のお家(うち)に済むことになったら
If Mommy and Daddy were
to live in different houses...
礼奈ちゃんは
どっちのお家に住みたい？
...whose house would
you want to live in?
えっと…
Um...
I'm thinking about separating
with Daddy and marrying Akihito.
お母さんね お父さんと別れて―
アキヒトおじさんと
結婚しようと思うの
えっ？
（母）お母さん 妊娠してるの
I am pregnant.
I won't go to your house.
Daddy's house is my house.
（ﾚﾅ）あなたの家には行きません
父の家が私の家です！
I don't want to see you again!
（ﾚﾅ）もう
あなたとも会いたくありません
（母）でもね 礼奈
お父さんのほうに残ったら―
But, Reina...
If you stay with Daddy,
your life now will be...
これからの生活も…
Don't call me Reina so easily.
私のこと 気安く
礼奈って呼ばないでください
No, Rena.
ダメだ レナ
You can't think
that you're unhappy.
不幸になったとか考えちゃいけない
私は幸せなんだ
I am happy.
絶対に幸せなんだ
I am definitely happy.
When They Cry
（ﾚﾅ）ただいま！
I'm home!
ハァ…
（ﾚﾅの父）おかえり
Welcome home.
オッ… 傘持ってなかったのかい？
（ﾚﾅ）朝は晴れてたから
You didn't have an umbrella?
Since it was sunny
in the morning.
Here.
（父）ほら
（ﾚﾅ）わあ…
Come to the living room.
There's something cool.
（父）居間へ来てごらん
ちょっと すごいぞ
W-What happened, Daddy?
ど… どうしたの？ お父さん
（父）まあ ちょっと 心機一転さ
I wanted to feel a little refreshed.
It's been a year
since we moved here...
もう引っ越してきて
１年にもなるんだから―
お父さんも
そろそろ気分を切り替えて―
...so I thought it's about
time I changed my mood...
新しい生活に
踏み出さないとなって思ったんだよ
...and stepped into a new life.
That's true.
そうだね エヘヘッ…
Anyone would feel nice
in a beautiful room like this.
こんな きれいなお部屋だと
心も晴れ晴れするもんね
I think it's a nice room.
ステキなお部屋だと思うよ
（父）うん やっぱりな
I thought so.
（父）
リナさんに選んでもらったんだ
I had Rina-san
choose them for me.
You're going to throw that away?
あれは捨てちゃうの？
（父）
ああ… まあ この際だと思ってな
Yeah, I thought now
might be a good time.
明日 業者が引き取りに
来てくれることになってる
The company will come
and get that tomorrow.
（ﾚﾅ）ふ～ん…
（父）
そうだ レナ すまないんだけど―
Oh, yeah, Rena. Sorry...
...but could you run an errand
for me after school tomorrow?
あしたの学校の帰りに
お使い 頼めないか？
An errand? Sure.
（ﾚﾅ）お使い？ うん いいよ
お父さんな
ジャケットを２着ほど―
I ordered two jackets from
a clothing store in Okinomiya.
興宮(おきのみや)の洋服屋さんに
注文してあるんだ
それを
代わりに取ってきてくれないか？
Could you pick them up for me?
（ﾚﾅ）うん いいよ
Sure.
Did Rina-san pick those for you?
それって
リナさんに見立ててもらったの？
ま… まあな
W-Well, yes.
へえ…
I see.
（店員）大変 申し訳ございません
I'm terribly sorry.
The delivery truck is caught
in traffic due to a car accident.
（店員）
実は 入荷のトラックが―
高速で
事故渋滞に巻き込まれていまして…
もうじき到着すると思うのですが…
I'm sure it'll arrive soon...
Okay...
（ドアベル）
（ｳｴｰﾄﾚｽ）いらっしゃいませ
Welcome!
（鉄平(てっぺい)）待たしょっちからに
How dare you keep me waiting.
I-I'm sorry.
（男性）す… すんまへん
（鉄平）ケッ！
What are you going to do?
（鉄平）…で どういうこった？
We'll try to do something.
（男性）
すんまへん なんとか その…
（鉄平）御託は ええねん ボケ！
とっとと うなる物(もん) さらさんかい！
Who cares about
this tedious talk.
All you gotta do is give
back what you borrowed.
（男性たち）アアッ… えっと…
This is all for now.
（男性）これで よろしゅう…
（鉄平）ンンッ！
（ｳｴｰﾄﾚｽ）
ご注文 お決まりですか？
Have you decided on your order?
あっ えっと…
Um...
アップルティーを
Apple tea.
Sure.
（ｳｴｰﾄﾚｽ）かしこまりました
- Hey, count them.
- Hey, don't order me.
おい 数えんね
（女性）ちょっと
私に命令しないでくれる？
じゃかましいわ！
黙って数えなええんね
Shut up!
Just shut up and count them!
Don't think you're all that.
It was originally my money.
威張んないでよ！
もともと私の金じゃない
いくらあった？
（女性）私が貸した分だけ
How much is there?
Just the amount I lent.
ボケが！ 利子は どうしたんね？
You idiots!
Where's the interest?
I-I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
（男性）す… すんまへん
えろう すんまへん
勘弁してください
Please forgive us!
He always gets all psyched
up when it comes to me.
（女性）
うちの人は 私のことになると―
す～ぐ頭に血が上っちゃうのよねえ
Yeah, that's right.
おお そうよ
この女は俺の体の一部なんね
This woman is part of my body.
If someone throws dirt on her,
then it's like throwing dirt on me.
この女に泥塗りくさるヤツは
俺に塗ったんと同じやんなぁ
血祭りじゃ済まんね
It won't be forgiven
just with blood.
S-Sorry! Sorry!
（男性たち）
す… すんません！ すんません！
Pay off all the interest today.
（女性）利子は
今日 きっちり払っちゃいなさい
Then you won't have
to deal with him anymore.
そうすれば とりあえず
あんなヤツとは縁切れるんだから
W-Well yeah, but...
そりゃそうですけど
でも 50万なんて
これ以上 もう払えないッス
But I can't pay
another 500,000 yen.
（女性）しょうがないわね
Well, fine.
You don't need any
collateral or solidarity.
（女性）担保も連帯も要らないんで
（女性）
ちょいと利率が あれだけど―
The interest is high, but it should
be better than dealing with him.
あいつのよりは
はるかにマシでしょう？
おう！ 話は ついたか？
Oh, is it settled?
おう おうおう 感心な若人だね
Well, what reliable young ones.
Men need some duties to fulfill.
男は
背負うもんがなくちゃ あかんねえ
（鉄平）そういや…
By the way, Ritsuko.
律子(りつこ)
お前の雛見沢の旦那 どうなんね？
How's your husband
in Hinamizawa?
How much do you think
you can squeeze out of him?
どのくらい搾れそうなんよ？
（女性）それがさ…
Listen to this.
別れた奥さんが だいぶ
慰謝料をくれたらしいってのは―
I heard his ex-wife paid him
a lot of consolation money...
聞いてたんだけど
ホントに
すっげえ あるらしいのよね
...and it really does
seem like he has a lot.
（鉄平）どのくらいに？
About how much?
He has about
50,000,000 yen in the bank.
銀行に5,000万くらい持ってるわよ
Since it's easy money...
（女性）あぶく銭なわけだし
...he's so generous.
- Here's your order.
もう気前がいいの何のって…
（ｳｴｰﾄﾚｽ）お待たせしました
（女性）
何でも買ってくれるのよ 何でも
He buys me anything
I want. Anything.
He's not super stingy like you.
Should I get serious with him?
あんたみたいなドケチとは大違い
私も本気になっちゃおうかしら？
（鉄平）抜かせ ボケ！
Whatever, you idiot.
Your body can't be
satisfied by anyone but me.
俺以外で満足できる体かっちゅう…
（女性）アア…
もう こんなとこで よしてよ
Not here.
…で 雛見沢の旦那
どう持ってくつもりなんよ？
So how'll you lure your
Hinamizawa husband?
あんたをダシに
手切れ金が要るって持ってくつもり
I'll use you and have him pay
in order to end my ties with you.
（鉄平）
つくづく恐ろしい女じゃんねえ
You're such a frightening chick.
（男性）
あの… すみません 書きました
Um, we've filled it in.
Okay. Let's go get the loan.
（鉄平）おう
じゃ それ持ってローン行こうか
Ritsuko, take care of the bill here.
律子 会計頼むね
Gosh...
（女性）もう！
（葛西(かさい)）うん？
（鉄平）ヘヘッ… どうも
Excuse us.
（女性）これは 総支配人
ご無沙汰しております
Well, long time
no see, general manager.
マスター
Master.
（ﾏｽﾀｰ）はい 何か？
Yes, sir.
T-This daily special dessert,
the s-sweet one...
こ… この日替わりデザートの
スイート何とかっていうのは―
Are you serving it today?
今日は やっているのか？
We don't have it today, but if
you'd like one, we can prepare it.
いえ 今日は やってないんですが
どうしてもと
おっしゃるんでしたら―
特別に ご用意を
ムリならムリと言ってくれればいい
If you can't, then say you can't.
Hey, Kasai!
（詩音(しおん)）ほ～ら 葛西！
He's saying he can
prepare it for you.
“特別に ご用意”って
言ってくれてるじゃないですか
ここまで来て みっともない！
Don't be embarrassed now.
じゃ 頼む
（ﾏｽﾀｰ）はい
Please.
- Yes.
- Me too.
同じのね
（ﾏｽﾀｰ）かしこまりました
Sure.
Hello!
（詩音）はろろ～ん！
レナさんじゃないですか
（ﾚﾅ）ハッ…
Rena-san, right?
こんにちは！
（ﾚﾅ）あっ 詩ぃちゃん？
Hello!
Shi-chan?
Yes, it's Shion.
はい 詩音で～す！
おや １人？
Oh, you're alone?
ひょっとして
圭ちゃんと待ち合わせかな？
Are you waiting for Kei-chan?
It's nothing like that.
そんなんじゃないよ
U-Um, Shi-chan?
あ… あの… 詩ぃちゃん
そのお連れの方は？
Who is that with you?
葛西です
He's Kasai.
I guess he's kinda
like my bodyguard.
まあ 私のボディーガードとか
思っといてください
If my life is in danger,
Kasai will save me, right?
私の命に危険が迫ったら
葛西が守ってくれるんだよね？
I won't.
（葛西）イヤです
ハハッ…
ねっ？ 面白いヤツでしょう
See, isn't he a funny guy?
あっ… えっと 葛西さん
Um, Kasai-san?
さっき すれ違った人たちは
お知り合いですか？
Do you know those
people who passed by before?
まあ…
Well...
（ﾚﾅ）どういう人たちなんですか？
What type of people are they?
The man is Teppei Hojo.
（葛西）男は北条(ほうじょう)鉄平
He's an ill-mannered junkie.
ちょいと礼儀知らずの雀(ジャン)ゴロです
（詩音）へえ…
I see.
How about the woman?
女の人のほうは？
Rina Mamiya.
間宮(まみや)リナ
源氏名だと思いましたが…
I believe that's
her hostess name.
Her real name is Ritsuko.
確か 律子って名前だったかと
（葛西）フラワーロードの
店のひとつで働いている水の女です
She works as a hostess at one
of the bars on Flower Road.
What type of people are they?
どういう人たちなんですか？
北条は確か リナのヒモのはずです
Hojo is probably Rina's pimp.
タチの悪い連中ですので―
They're dangerous, so you
shouldn't get involved with them.
関わり合いになられないほうが
いいと思います
How dangerous?
どうタチが悪いんですか？
（葛西）女の私生活には
触れないのが仁義ってもんです
Out of courtesy, I don't touch
on a woman's personal life.
（ﾚﾅ）どうタチが悪いんですか？
（葛西）それは ご勘弁を
How dangerous?
Forgive me.
どうタチが悪いんですか！
レナさん？
Rena-san?
Kasai.
葛西 意地悪しないで
教えてあげなさいよ
Don't be mean and tell her.
It doesn't seem like she's
just asking out of curiosity.
（詩音）興味本位で
聞いてるわけじゃなさそうだしさ
Those two are
dangerous hoodlums.
あの２人はタチの悪いゴロツキです
I heard they live off of
threatening others and gambling.
恐喝と博打(ばくち)で
生計を立てていると聞いています
（葛西）美人局(つつもたせ)もやるって話です
I heard they also
pull a badger game.
What do you mean by badger?
（ﾚﾅ）美人局って 何ですか？
美人局ってのは 要するに―
It's an old blackmail scheme,
where a girl hooks up with a guy...
カモと女をくっつけて
いい感じになったところで―
...gets along with him, and
another guy barges in, yelling...
男が乱入して
“自分の女に何しやがる”って―
..."What are you doing with my
girl?" and demands big bucks.
金を巻き上げる古典的な恐喝
でも まあ
鼻の下を伸ばした代償なわけだし
But you end up paying the price
for getting close to a woman.
自業自得ってね
（葛西）
そんな言い方はないもんです
You shouldn't put it that way.
Men do sometimes
get tricked by women.
男は 時にコロッと
女にダマされちまうもんですよ
ほう… なに？ それ
What do you mean? Who's
the woman who tricked you?
葛西をコロッとダマした女って誰？
（葛西）フゥ…
マスター！
デザートをこちらのレナさんにも…
Master, please bring another
dessert for Rena-san...
うん？
（詩音）…て あれ？
Huh?
（ドアベル）
（葛西）今 お帰りになりましたよ
She just left.
I wonder what
happened to Rena-san.
（詩音）
どうしたのかな？ レナさん
To get my happiness,
I had done everything...
...but had done nothing
to be blamed and accused of.
The sound of footsteps
became louder every day.
Then I noticed the fact
there was no time.
I was a believer in life,
to be myself always.
And was asking
whether I would be alive.
Give me a reason
why not to adopt in this way.
Or judge me to be guilty
of so many incurable sins.
Tell me why or why not?
Complaining way too much.
Maybe I overlooked
something fatal for me.
Preview
What is carried out
are thoughts of happiness.
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）貫くのは 幸せへの思い
What is avoided are
promises made with friends.
交わされるのは 友との決め事
救われるのは ひとときの迷い
What is saved is
the moment of perplexity.
「ひぐらしのなく頃に」
When They Cry.
"Atonement" Chapter,
Episode 2: PLACE TO RETURN.
- "Atonement" Chapter -
Episode 02: PLACE TO RETURN
"Atonement" Chapter,
Episode 2: PLACE TO RETURN.
あなたは信じられますか？
- "Atonement" Chapter -
Episode 02: PLACE TO RETURN
Can you believe it?